Damian Lesch

PRODUCTION MANAGER, PROCESS/CHEMICAL ENGINEER

Profile

Multi-talented Production Manager experienced in diverse industrial environments. Profit-motivated collaborator with ingenuity in troubleshooting complex productivity obstacles. Creative leader with motivational supervisory methods. Proactive and successful at anticipating needs and making adjustments to schedules, materials and workflow. Ready to bring expertise to company needing hands-on, knowledgeable and resourceful leader.

Employment History

Night Club Manager, Cellars, Paarl

DECEMBER 2022 — FEBRUARY 2023

- Staff Management
- Cash up and stock take
- Customer Liaison
- Stock Level Management
- Design and Development of Cash up System

Production Manager, Kwanza Sands Minerals (Previously CIM), Cape Town

OCTOBER 2017 — MAY 2022

Managing and Planning the Operation of the Production dept. (Glass Sand Plant and Mining)

- Regular performance appraisals with reportees
- Delegating and managing tasks among the production team
- Meeting production requirements
- Process improvement (R&D)
- Legally appointed under regulation 2.6.1 of the mine health and safety act No.29 of 1996 $\,$
- Regular reporting on production stats to the mine manager as well as the group $\ensuremath{\mathsf{CEO}}$
- Acting mine manager in the absence of the mine manager
- Compiling quarterly and annual production technical reports

Plant Engineer (EIT), Consol Industrial Minerals, Cape Town

FEBRUARY 2015 — OCTOBER 2017

- Planning and executing projects
- Upgrading the SOP and operating manuals on site
- Combustion Chamber Replacement Project Management
- Technical Drawing and Conceptual Design
- Process Control and Management
- Process Improvement

Details

0663060692 ddlesch88@gmail.com

Skills

Computer Skills

Ability to Work Under Pressure

Ability to Work in a Team

Adaptability

Teamwork

Microsoft Office Word

Fast Learner

Communication

Microsoft PowerPoint

Microsoft Excel

Project Management

Leadership

Microsoft Office

Education

BSc Chemistry and Polymer Science, University of Stellenbosch, Stellenbosch

JANUARY 2007 — DECEMBER 2010

The focus of the program was on organic, inorganic, analytical, physical and polymer chemistry fields with applied math and statistics as additional majors. Computational chemistry was explored with the aim of further development in post graduate studies.

BEng Chemical, University of Stellenbosch, Stellenbosch

JANUARY 2011 — DECEMBER 2014

The course was comprised of training in the theoretical knowledge of engineering practices and industry. Introduction to industrial processes and process design techniques were focussed on. I completed a course on process design whereby I was required to research and design an ethanol production plant from waste paper pulp. My research topic was the on the improvement of the reaction kinetics of the transesterification reaction in the production of biodiesel from waste cooking oil.

Courses

BMS 200 Management Skills Program, Dyna

FEBRUARY 2017 — APRIL 2017

Courageous Conversations, Psygro

MAY 2018 — MAY 2018

References

William Lilly from Kwanza Sands Minerals (Projects Manager Mining SA)

wlilly@consol.co.za · 0833829184

Jessi Daniels from Consol Glass (Consol Glass HR Business Partner)

jdaniels@consol.co.za · 082 927 9390

Justin Arendse (Reportee: Production Foreman)

jarendse@consol.co.za 071 774 4467